Guide to the Roger Imhof Vaudeville, variety, circus, and silent screen star scrapbooks, 1883-1952
Department of Special Collections
Roger Imhof Vaudeville, variety, circus, and silent screen star scrapbooks,
1883-1952
Special Collections M0611
Imhof, Roger, 1875-1958, collector.
7 linear ft. (48 v.)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Samuel Stark, 1964. Stark met Imhof sometime in the '40s.
Biographical Note
Frederick Roger Imhoff was born in Roca Island, Illinois, 15 April, 1875. Although very little biographical information on Imhof exists in either the Sam Stark Index or the Imhof Scrapbook Collection, it seems Imhof must have had connections in theater even in his childhood. Scrapbooks of vaudeville and burlesque show programs he collected date back to the late 1880s, and by 1897 (if not before), Imhof was himself on stage, teamed with Charles Osborne in a comedy contortion and burlesque acrobatics act. It was around this time that Imhof dropped the second f from his last name (he apparently always preferred Roger).
The 1902-03 season was his first paired with Hugh Conn, a partnership that lasted well into the '20s and possibly even '30s. By the 1910s the duo had become a trio with the addition of Marcelle Coreene, who married Imhof around 1913 (it is unclear to me whether Marcelle Coreene and Corinne Imhof are actually the same person; both names appear in playbills of the Imhof and Conn acts).
It seems Imhof, while not completely dropping out of vaudeville, was able to get involved with the infant American film industry in Hollywood very early. Though Stark mentions on his Imhof index card that Imhof was a film actor, Imhof's real career in Hollywood seems to have been as a presenter, promoter, or agent. According to a few comments and articles sprinkled among his scrapbooks, Imhof was acquainted with such silent film celebrities as Gloria Swanson, Rudolph Valentino, and Max Sennett and his group.
Imhof actually stayed in Hollywood for the next three decades, and his scrapbooks show that he was part of the American motion picture scene throughout the '30s, '40s, and '50s. Friends and clients of his included the likes of Susan Hayward, Rita Hayworth, Janet Leigh, Judy Garland, Mickey Rooney, Roy Rogers, Gregory Peck, and hundreds of others.
It is unclear just how Imhof and Sam Stark met, but it must have been sometime in the '40s, for that's when Stark seems to have started receiving old scrapbooks from Imhof. Roger Imhof died on his birthday in 1958 in Hollywood, California. Included in the Sam Stark Theater Collection are 50 or more of Imhof's scrapbooks, pictorially documenting American entertainment from vaudeville to Hollywood's Golden Age.
Scope and Content
A pictorial documentation of American entertainment from vaudeville through Hollywood's golden age. Includes songs and lyrics by Roger Imhof.
Access Terms
Conn, Hugh L.; Coreene, Marcelle.; Circus--United States.; Lyric writing (Popular music); Mimes.; Motion pictures--History.; Mumming.; Musicals--Writing and publishing.; Theater.; Toy theaters.; Vaudeville--United States.; Hollywood (Calif.)--History.; Lyricsts. lcsh; Stark, Samuel.
Container List
- 1883vaudeville, theatre programs (Box 1, Volume 1)
- 1889-90vaudeville season programs (Box 1, Volume 2)
- 1890vaudeville season programs (Box 1, Volume 3)
- 1903-04season programs, Conn and Imhof shows (Box 1, Volume 4)
- 1900-1930vaudeville, theatre, burlesque programs (Box 1, Volume 5)
- embroidered signatures scrapbook, 1880-1950 (Box 1, Volume 6)
- A Few I Knew As I Older Grew - index of names; 50 years of the Varieties (1943) (Box 2, Volume 7)
- Pictorial Vaudeville and Variety: Sequel to A Few I Knew As I Older Grew (1930) (Box 2, Volume 8)
- Roger Imhof's Artists - black and white pics of vaudevillians (Box 2, Volume 9)
- Some of Vaudeville's Big Shots and Moving Picture Pioneers (Box 2, Volume 10)
- Roger Imhof's Way Back When Old Timers (Box 2, Volume 11)
- Troupers (Box 2, Volume 12)
- Roger Imhof's Memories (Box 2, Volume 13)
- Pictures of Theatre Folks in the Magazines - Vol. 4 - Short Histories and Pictures (issues of The New Movie Album, Hollywood Who's Who, Modern Screen, Movie Story Magazine, Stage Pictorial, Movie Life) (Box 2, Volume 14)
- Flashbacks - Showfolks - Vol. 5 - Picture People (Box 2, Volume 15)
- Jocosites Bound and Gagged (mostly pics of silent screen stars, 1920s-30s) (Box 3, Volume 16)
- Variety Folk (1930s-40s) (Box 3, Volume 17)
- Mimes and Mimics Big and Little (1940s) (Box 3, Volume 18)
- Co-Workers - Stage and Screen (1940s) (Box 3, Volume 19)
- Entertainers (1940s) (Box 3, Volume 20)
- Boys and Girls of the Pictures, Big and Little ('48) (Box 3, Volume 21)
- Male and Female Mummers ('49) (Box 3, Volume 22)
- I Knew Them All (1940s-50s) (Box 3, Volume 23)
- Pals and Players (1950) (Box 3, Volume 24)
- Players ('52) (Box 3, Volume 25)
- Scrapbooks containing miscellaneous songs, musicals by Imhof, humorous pieces, etc.
  - Signatures 1935 (Box 4, Volume 26)
  - Biography (short bios of various celebrities) (Box 4, Volume 27)
  - Circus Articles (Box 4, Volume 28)
  - Records (truly miscellaneous) (Box 4, Volume 29)
  - Flashbacks - Letterheads & Articles (and old numbers of Variety) (Box 4, Volume 30)
  - Roger Imhof's Collection of Old Time Songs (Box 4, Volume 31)
  - Thoughts by Roger Imhof (Box 4, Volume 32)
  - Songs and Poems by Roger Imhof (Box 4, Volume 33)
  - Original Lyrics - Topical Sentimental Descriptive (Box 5, Volume 34)
  - On the Fire - More Songs and Lyrics by Roger Imhof (Box 5, Volume 35)
  - Songs and Lyrics by Roger Imhof (Box 5, Volume 36)
  - Bonmots, What-Nots, and Forget-Me-Nots - An Accumulation of Humor (Vol. 8) (Box 5, Volume 37)
  - BWF Humor, Vol. 3 (Box 5, Volume 38)
  - Facts We Should Know (Box 5, Volume 39)
  - Trivia (Box 5, Volume 40)
  - Index to Pictorial Vaudeville Vols 1-3 (but those volumes aren't marked; some song lyrics, too) (Box 5, Volume 41)
- Old theatrical trade papers, bound as books
  - The Show World, December 21, 1907Variety, December 26, 1919 (Box 6, Volume 42)
  - Old Numbers of Theatrical Trade Papers (various ones, dated 1911-1919, 1922, '25, '26, '34 (Box 6, Volume 43)
  - more of same, dated 1922-37 (Box 6, Volume 44)
  - more of same, dated Dec. 1914, Dec. 1915, Dec. 1924, August 1936reproduction of a 1911issue (Box 6, Volume 45)
  - more of same, dated 1912, '13, '15, '21, '27, '35, '36 (Box 6, Volume 46)
- Pictorial Shakespeare (big flat folio) (Box 7, Volume 47)
- Roger Imhof's Collection of Old Timers (more old trade magazines) (Box 7, Volume 48)